你说对了 乔治
You were right, George.
我们中有叛徒
We have a traitor in the house.
这上面有五个名字
There are five names on there.
你妻子也是其中之一
Your wife’s one of them.
为什么
Why is that?
你让我查所有人
You asked me to look at everyone.
我查了
I looked.
她有权限 有动机
She has the security clearance, she has the motive,
也有能力
and she has the capability.
我必须得把她列进去
I had to put her down.
你大概要多久
How long do you think you’ll need?
给我两周时间
Give me two weeks.
如果他们真的按计划用了死危病毒
If Severus is deployed as intended,
上千无辜的人都会死
thousands of innocent people will die.
好吧 一周
Okay. One week.
如果真是凯瑟琳 你真的下得了手吗
If it is Kathryn, do you really think you can do that?
安娜怎么样了
How’s Anna?
还气着呢
Still mad.
-很抱歉 -我犯了一个错误 就这样
-I’m sorry. -I made a mistake, that’s all.
她没法放下
She just can’t let it go.
她会的 最终会的
She will, eventually.
真的
Yeah?
有些事情最好的处理方式就是避而不谈
Some things really are best swept under the rug.
我就是觉得要是没那么简单就好了
I just wish it wasn’t so fucking easy.
出轨
To cheat.
对我们来说
For us.
嗯哼
Mm.
不是所有人都向往你那样明目张胆的一夫一妻制 乔治
Not everyone aspires to your flagrant monogamy, George.
如果你想让安娜消消气
If you’d like Anna to be less angry,
可以考虑回趟家
you might consider going home.
祝你顺利找到内奸
Good luck finding the rat.
我能感觉到你在盯着我看
I can feel when you’re watching me.
抱歉
Sorry.
我很喜欢
I like it.
我知道这不是你喜欢的那种
I understand this is not
简单的晚餐
the casual dinner you’d prefer.
是啊 这次是群不同寻常的人
Yeah. It’s an unusual group.
数据收集员 两名特工 还有个内部的心理医生
Data scraper, two agents and the in-house shrink.
我们这次要找什么
What are we hunting this time?
死危病毒
Severus.
你觉得他们中有人拿了
And you think one of them took it?
有可能
Possibly.
嗯
Hmm.
咱们有段时间没请叛徒共进晚餐了
It’s been a while since we had a traitor to dinner.
至少是在已知有叛徒的情况下
At least knowingly.
我们不该讨论这个
We shouldn’t be discussing this.
是啊 大概不该讨论
No, probably not.
我以为你要从测谎仪开始
I would’ve thought you’d start with polygraphs.
我想试试一开始优雅一些
I wanted to try something more elegant first.
菜单上有什么
What’s on the menu?
乐趣和游戏
Fun and games.
事后需要清理现场吗
Will there be a mess to clean up?
如果进展顺利的话
With any luck.
-它们很适合你 -嗯
-They suit you. -Mm.
不你花太多钱了
No, you spent too much.
你总这么在意钱也太无趣了
It’s boring how much you think about money.
你总这么不在乎钱也太吓人了
It’s terrifying how much you don’t.
别吃鹰嘴豆咖喱
Avoid the chana masala.
里面有一定量的DZM 5
Contains a healthy amount of DZM 5.
亲爱的 你可不能给我们的客人下药啊
Darling, you may not dose our guests.
他们中有人在说谎
One of them is a liar.
我想知道是谁
I want to know which.
我从没想过这会发生
♪ I never thought it would happen ♪
在我和克拉珀姆的那个女孩身上
♪ With me and the girl from Clapham ♪
在那刮风的公地上
♪ Out on the windy common ♪
那一夜我至今难忘
♪ That night I ain’t forgotten ♪
她分配着生活所需
♪ When she dealt out the rations ♪
带着一些激情
♪ With some or other passions... ♪
-马修 -您好 先生
-Matthew. -Hello, sir.
我想给靠门的那桌买单
I want to settle up for the table by the door.
-当然 -然后我要双份的尊美醇威士忌
-Of course. -And I’ll have a double Jameson.
马上先生
Straightaway, sir.
我知道他们其实也没有那么老
I know they’re not that much older, really,
但我还是觉得像是要去我爸妈家一样
but I kind of feel like I’m going to my parents’ house.
如果我爸妈没离婚也不恨彼此的话
If-if they weren’t divorced and didn’t hate each other.
反正 我知道的是
Well, here’s what I know.
不会有人两次邀请你共进晚餐
You don’t get invited to dinner twice
如果你第一次拒绝了他们的话
if you say no the first time.
但为什么是现在
But why now?
还只提前24小时通知
With 24 hours’ notice?
以及为什么是我们?
And why us?
我们都在一起工作啊
We all work together.
请两对在同一领域工作的夫妻 也没那么牵强
Two couples in the same field. It’s not that much of a reach.
所以你觉得是他们自发想邀请我们
So you believe this was just spontaneous?
至少在我看到其他征兆之前会这么认为
I’m assuming so until I see reason to believe otherwise.
你和弗雷迪要面对面坐
You and Freddie sitting across from each other
即使在那件事之后
after what just happened?
他可能是在挑衅你
That could be read as provocative.
弗雷迪挺好的
Freddie’s fine.
对吧
Right?
我怎么会知道
How should I know?
问心理医生去
Ask the shrink.
你们觉得是谁想出来请我们的呢
Whose idea was it, do you think?
-乔治还是凯瑟琳 -乔治
-George or Kathryn? -STOKES and CLARISSA: George.
-抱歉抱歉 非常抱歉 -天呐 弗雷迪
-Sorry, sorry. So sorry. -For fuck’s sake, Freddie.
明明是你订的桌子
I mean, you booked the table.
是你想在赴宴前碰头的
You’re the one that wanted to meet beforehand.
完全是我的错 我承认
I am absolutely at fault, I admit it.
沃恩医生 如果她可以这么说的话
And Dr. Vaughan, were she allowed to say so,
会说我的长期迟到行为中
would claim there’s a certain hostility
带有某种敌意
in my chronic tardiness.
但为了弥补你们
But in order to make it up to you all,
我已经给大家结完了帐 并给了很多小费
I have paid the bill and tipped like a gangster.
哦 拜托
Oh, come on.
我们相聚在此是要庆祝詹姆斯实至名归的
We are celebrating James’s well-deserved,
飞速晋升
meteoric ascent through the ranks.
干杯
Cheers.
-走吗 -好
-Shall we? -Right.
等等
Wait.
我以为你会给我点建议呢 之后该怎么表现
I was hoping for some pointers. I mean, how shall I behave?
称赞他的厨艺 然后一切都会好的
Praise his cooking, and I promise all will be magical.
-嗨 -凯瑟琳
- Hello. - Kathryn.
-嗨 -非常准时
-Hello. -On time and everything.
-进来吧 -谢谢
-Come in. -Thank you.
这个给我吧
Oh, shall I take that?
不用 我拿到厨房
No, I’ll take it to the kitchen.
快进来吧 是啊 外面很冷吧
Come in. Yes, it’s cold, isn’t it?
嗨
Hello.
-很高兴见到你 -好了
-Lovely to see you. -All right.
-把外套给我吧 -哇
-I should take your coat. -Wow.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们的房子 真漂亮
This is, um... beautiful.
哦 是吗
Oh, yeah.
这就是没孩子的快乐 对吧
The joys of not having children, hey?
-你想喝点什么 -朗姆
-What would you like to drink? -Rum.
-朗姆 -嗯哼
-Rum. -Mmm.
-98年的红酒 -对
-’98 for the table. -Right.
真是太棒了
Oh, yes, lovely.
我们赶紧把这事聊开吧
Should we get this over with?
我懂你为什么选他
I get it, why you went with him.
-是吗 -詹姆斯是明智之选
-Yes? -James is the smart play.
年轻 积极进取 而且
Young, aggressive and...
该怎么说呢
How shall we say it?
还没叛变
Uncompromised.
我一直希望是你
I’d always hoped it would be you.
我喝太多酒 操太多人
I drink too much, I fuck too much,
还欠了一屁股债
and I owe more than I’m worth.
药也成了一个问题
The pills are becoming a problem as well.
我很庆幸能向你吐露我的真心 乔治
I’m so glad I can confide in you, George.
我得去换衣服了
I need to change.
放过他们吧
Oh, give them a break.
国家网络安全中心里大多数都是25岁左右的小孩
Most of NCSC is 25-year-olds.
他们都在瞎胡闹呢
They were just mucking around,
试图对一台核心路由器进行零日攻击
trying to zero-day a central router.
他们也没想到能把整个系统搞崩溃
They didn’t know they’d brick the whole system.
等会儿 叙利亚 2012?
Wait. Syria 2012?
那是你们干的
That was you?
-是我们干的 -我不知道
-That was us? -I don’t know.
我不在那边工作
I don’t work on that side of the house.
那次任务做得干净利落 我看过相关文件
That op was tight. I’ve read that string.
代码也很漂亮
It’s a very sexy piece of code.
一切都安然无恙 直到斯诺登冒出头来
Mm. It was all fine till little Eddie Snowden
把所有人暴露了个精光 真是个烂摊子
decided to call everybody out, said it was a fuckup.
那之后阿萨德就被关停了 不是吗
It shut Assad’s ass right down, didn’t it?
死了多少平民
How many civilians died as a result?
为了更伟大的利益
Greater good.
没道德的人都不怎么样
Yeah, I don’t find amorality attractive.
那你只好要么放弃工作 要么放弃性生活了
Then give up either your profession or your sex life.
我猜 两周吧
I give it two weeks.
太乐观了
Optimistic.
上峰为难你了吗
Did you get hell from oversight?
-没什么 -拜托
-Nothing I couldn’t handle. -Oh, please.
委员会只让凯瑟琳不好过了一次
The committee fucked with Kathryn exactly once.
一半的委员就丢掉了任务
Half of them lost their assignments.
睚眦必报嘛
’Cause that’s what bad bitches do.
对了 鹰嘴豆咖喱真好吃
Chana masala is fantastic, by the way.
非常美味
Absolutely delicious.
-嗯 -谢谢
- Mm. - Thank you.
拜托
Come on.
我们在叙利亚干的事可不算是最糟糕的
Syria’s hardly the worst thing we’ve ever done.
我曾经曝光过我孩子的老师是个恋童癖
I once outed my kid’s teacher as a pedophile
就为了把他炒掉
just to get him fired.
哦
Oh.
猜到了
Figures.
结果发现那个人的八岁小孩长了皮疹
Turns out the guy’s eight-year-old had a rash.
他真不应该发那些照片
Guess he shouldn’t have emailed those pictures.
真是让人讨厌 弗雷迪
That is uniquely loathsome, Freddie.
看图说话嘛 怎么对我有利怎么来
You hand me an angle, I play it.
新来的老师现在给Matty打分是A
New teacher gave Matty an "A."
-少惹在特工爸爸们 -我们都是烂人
-Don’t fuck with SIS dad. -So we’re all horrible people.
这是你想说的重点
Is that what the point is here?
我想说的是 「复杂」 的人
I prefer to say "complex."
「爱国」有什么不对吗
And what’s wrong with "patriotic"?
得了吧 我们大部分人都是神经病
Come on, most of us are sick as shit.
俄狄浦斯来了都得管他叫大哥
Nobody can lay a glove on Oedipus over there.
你们不知道吗
What, you all don’t know about that?
-注意点 弗雷迪 -大家都知道
-Careful, Freddie. -It’s common knowledge.
那是他自己的事 你少管
Well, that’s for him, not you.
没事 不过谢谢你 亲爱的
It’s all right. But thank you, darling.
看到了吧
See?
-乔治不介意的 -什么事
-George can handle it. -Handle what?
小乔治监视了他亲爸
Little Georgie surveilled his own father.
啊
Ouch.
天哪
Oh, my.
好吧
Well...
亲爱的爸爸是个劈腿渣男
Daddy was an inveterate cheater.
管不住下半身
Rarely if ever kept it in his pants.
但他干这行很久了 而且 怎么说呢
But he was senior service, and he was,
人很谨慎
shall we say, careful.
当你半生都活在黑袋里
When half your life’s in the black bag,
一个普通的平民妻子怎么可能知道
how’s little civilian wifey ever gonna have a prayer
你在哪里四处留情
of knowing where you’re sticking it?
-真粗俗 -托马斯·伍德豪斯就是粗俗的代名词
-That’s crass. -So was Thomas Woodhouse.
他儿子可不喜欢这一点
And his boy didn’t like that one bit.
发生了什么
So what happened?
乔治抓住了他的小辫子
George got the goods on him.
录下来了
On video.
在一次周日家庭晚餐时当众播放
Played the tape one Sunday night at a family dinner
我倒贴钱也想看看这一幕
I would have paid money to be present at.
乔治把他爸的婚姻
George torched Daddy’s marriage
连着他爸的职业生涯一下子毁了
and his career at the same time.
没人会雇佣一个被自己儿子搞了的特工
Who will ever hire a field op who’s bested by his own kid?
我不喜欢骗子
I don’t like liars.
你很酷
You are so rock and roll.
这一定给人造成了不小的心理创伤
That must have been deeply traumatic.
你当时多大
How old were you?
37岁
Thirty-seven.
哦
Oh.
你父亲不知道你是做什么的吗
Did your father not know what you do for a living?
他知道的
Oh, no, he knew.
托马斯自认为他道高一尺
Thomas just thought he was very good.
乔治则是魔高一丈
George was better.
我听说你在审讯室从未失手
I hear you’ve never been beaten in the chair.
简直是个神话
You’re like some kind of legend.
没人能骗过你 真的吗
Is it true? No one can lie to you?
你不想知道的
Better not to find out.
你什么时候给我测个谎 乔治
Well, when are you gonna poly me, George?
抱歉
Sorry.
当然后来发生的事
Of course, what came after
也不能怪在乔治身上
can hardly be blamed on George.
够了
I think that’s enough.
这个男人郁闷了三十年
The man had been depressed for 30 years.
弗雷迪 别说了
Freddie, it ends.
-住嘴 -别他妈说了
- Right now. - Shut the fuck up
你跟人说话的时候 弗雷迪
when you talk to people, Freddie.
我想到个游戏
I have a game.
我们轮着来 每人说一个愿望
We go around the table and each of us makes a resolution.
像新年愿望有一样
The way you might at New Year.
需要改进的个人问题
Some personal issue that needs to be addressed.
比如说「我要戒烟」
"I resolve to quit smoking," for example.
真是前所未闻 乔治
Oh, this is some groundbreaking shit, George.
不过我们不给自己许愿
But we don’t make the resolution for ourselves.
而是给右手边的人许
We make it for the person to our right.
真的吗
I’m not sure that’s a good idea.
这主意可不太好
I’m certain it’s a terrible one.
你开玩笑呢吗
Are you joking?
他好像是认真的
I don’t believe he is.
-我来玩 -我再开一瓶酒
-I’m in. -I’m getting another bottle.
这可是新的
This is a new one.
Brand-new.
我可不知道情报局会追踪这个
Well, I wasn’t aware the agency would track that,
不过我会记着的
but I’ll, um... I’ll keep it in mind.
谢谢你 乔治
Thank you, George.
你说的「色情小说」
So, when you say "erotic fiction..."
别烦她了
Leave the poor woman alone.
我不需要别人维护我
I don’t need defending.
我喜欢看点黄文
I like a dirty story.
又不犯法
It’s not a crime.
到我了
I believe it’s my turn.
嗯
Yeah?
好
Okay.
我决定
"I resolve to... "
等等 我是不是应该用他的腔调说话
Wait, I’m speaking in his voice, yeah?
好吧
Okay.
我许愿 之后会尽力
"I resolve to do my best
在别人之后再高潮
to finish second whenever possible."
至少要一次
Or once, even.
做到一次就是很大的改变了
Once would be a refreshing change of pace.
-真不错 姐妹 -相信我
-Sing it, sister. -Trust me,
总有一天你会庆幸你自己还能高潮呢
one day, you’ll be thrilled to finish at all.
你真没正形 弗雷迪
You are so full of shit, Freddie.
嗯嗯 你到时候会求着我停的
Note taken. You’ll be begging me to stop.
哦 每个女人都想要这个
Oh, what every woman longs for.
一眼望不到头的 恼人的体验
An endless, abrasive experience.
继续吧
Let’s move on.
到我了
My turn.
是给你许愿望 对吧
This one’s for you, right?
好
Okay.
我要弄明白
"I resolve to figure out
我的恋老癖
this old man obsession of mine."
哦
Oh.
我很早就明白了 亲爱的
I figured that one out a long time ago, hon.
年轻男人无趣死了
Young men bore the shit out of me.
我是说 你们什么都没做过
I mean, you, you know, you haven’t done anything.
哪也没去过 你们只想
You haven’t been anywhere. All you want to do
把我邀请过去看你们打游戏
is invite me over to watch you play video games.
天哪
Oh, God.
我说对了吗
Did I get that one right?
第二次约会
Second date:
《使命召唤：太平洋战区》
Call of Duty: Pacific Theater.
这次聚会真是
Well, this has been
-让人心情愉悦 -我可能年龄大了
- absolutely delightful. - I may be old
但是至少我知道
and wizened, but at least I know
怎样预定一家好餐厅 少校
how to book a decent restaurant, Major.
-是上校 -好的 Xbox上校
-It’s Colonel. -Colonel Xbox.
-行吧 -我的世界少校
-Okay. -Major Minecraft.
真太他妈逗了 伙计
Fucking hilarious shit, mate.
他能一边玩塞尔达一边跟你快活
Promise you’ll go down on him while he plays Zelda
哪有个上校的样子 你说是吧
so he can die a happy little soldier, won’t you?
闭嘴吧你 弗雷迪
Shut the fuck up, Freddie.
你今天晚上吃错药了吗
What is your problem tonight?
谁说不是呢 如果不是脑子有问题
You know, the real problem with old men
我怎么会和老男人在一起 简直让人窒息
is the miserable, suffocating fear of death.
是个人都能感觉到
I mean, it’s there, so... so they can feel it,
但他们都敢怒不敢言
and they are quite literally pissing themselves with fear,
更可悲的是
which I-I suppose explains
这些老男人的生殖器会到处找家
their pathetic, priapic lunging at anything that moves.
我说你是不是喝昏了头
I’m wondering if perhaps you’ve had enough to drink.
现在你是玩不起吗
But it’s my turn now, right?
现在是轮到我给弗雷迪说 对吧
I get to speak for Freddie now, right?
「我保证不会再和她发生关系了」
"I’m gonna stop fucking her."
这我恐怕做不到 你这么美
Well, I’m afraid I can’t, gorgeous.
我在你面前毫无抵抗力
I am powerless before you.
不是我
Not me.
是那个女的
Her.
这是恶作剧吗
Is this some sort of prank?
所以说不要和情报局的人在一起
This is why you can’t date SIGINT.
全都他妈的疯子
They’re all fucking insane.
你缓一缓心情
It would appear...
缓完出来我们谈一谈
it would appear my young friend and I might benefit
就我们两个人
from a private conversation.
我哪儿都不去
I’m not going anywhere.
我告诉你
I am...
也许下周一你们两个
You know, maybe on Monday, the two of you
可以找个时间来我办公室
could find a few minutes to come by my office.
我们坐下来好好谈一谈
We could sit down and then...
-我说了哪儿都不去 -天呐 你简直无理取闹
-I’m not going anywhere. -My God, you are an infant.
-问题不在这 -你就是个精神病
-It’s not the issue. -You’re psychotic.
你就是有病
Pathological.
我一直以来满足你的病态需求
I have indulged your constant need for support
一直支持你 鼓励你 安慰你
and encouragement and reassurance
跟养女儿一样养了你一年半
and fucking paternal engagement for a year and a half now,
简直恶心死了
and I’m sick to fucking death of it.
爸爸走了
He left.
爸爸离开了我们 我好难过
I’m so sorry Daddy walked out the door,
可能是他不爱你妈妈
probably because he didn’t love Mummy,
但也有可能是他实在受够了
but maybe because he became so hopelessly bored
受够了你那些幼稚无脑的需求
with your needy, constant demands
然后他发现离开就解脱了
that he figured getting out was better!
实在是可怜 但发生了就是发生了
And that is a shitting tragedy, but it happens.
所以你要开始往前看
It happens, and you move on!
这才是一个正常人会做的事
That’s what a healthy human being does.
你就是一个彻彻底底的变态
You are a perversion of what a man is supposed to be.
-你给我闭嘴 -你就是有病
- Stop it. - You are a diseased creature
花了整整20年的时间
who has spent the last 20 years of her life
像个疯子一样团团转
running in frantic circles, trying to compensate
困在这个悲剧里
for a so-called tragedy that is quite possibly
而这个所谓的悲剧实际上什么都不是
the most boring story ever told,
而我 还陪你疯了这么久
and I’ve had it with you.
我恨你 我他妈的简直是瞎了眼
I hate you. I hate you so fucking much!
过去一年里
I have slept with no one but you
我只睡了你一个人
for the past year and a half,
你这个疯子
you sweet fucking lunatic!
就你一个
No one!
现在我真是后悔死了
And, my God, how I regret it now.
求求你了
Get some help!
放过我们这些
And stop spraying your sickness on the rest of us,
忠诚且正经的男同胞吧
on the loyal, faithful, decent men
我们只会真心爱一个人不留余地
who have only tried to love you
别跟有病一样天天折磨我们好吗
as well and as truly as they possibly could.
克勒肯威尔的泽特酒店
The Zetter Hotel in Clerkenwell.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
你经常光顾的那家酒店
That’s the hotel you prefer.
一般是在每周一和每周日去光顾
Normally, Mondays and Thursdays,
因为这个时间是部门会议
easiest for you because it’s the department meetings
你可以悄悄溜走
and you can slip away.
你的情人会用她自己的信用卡订房
Your lover pays with a credit card in her own name.
你应该会用现金还她 但这不重要
I assume you split it in cash, but that’s immaterial.
她叫什么也不重要
As is her name.
重要的是你最喜欢那套可以俯瞰整座城市的初级套房
The junior suite with city view is your favorite.
我说了我不喜欢说谎的人
I don’t like liars.
我的天 别动 不要动
Fucking hell! Wait, don’t move it.
不要动 别踏马动了
Don’t move it. Don’t fucking move it!
我来处理
Okay, I got it. I got it. I got it.
这是你最无聊的招
That is the most boring thing you’ve ever done.
-把手放下 -不要移动
-Hands down. -Stay still. Stay still.
看着我 看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
好样的 你给我等着瞧
All right, I’ll swap you.
-好 -把手臂给我
- Okay. - Give me the arm.
我在想你是不是用药过猛了
I wonder if it’s possible you went just a bit heavy
你的吐真剂
on the DZM 5.
也许吧
I may well have.
刚刚你看出什么来了吗
Did you see what you needed to see?
还没有
I don’t know yet.
今晚只是个引子 马上好戏开场
That was the rock. Now I watch the ripples.
先别收拾了
Leave the rest.
马上
I will.
两分钟就好
Just give me two minutes.
别管了
Leave it.
马上就来
I will.
它是干什么的
What does it do?
什么是干什么的
What does what do?
死危病毒(赛维鲁斯)
Severus.
这恐怕不能告诉你
I’m afraid that’s in the black bag.
那我来猜一猜
Want me to guess?
别
No.
是下三滥的手段吗 比如说能让整个政府瘫痪的恶意软件
Dirty tricks, malware, meant to disable a government.
为什么这么说
Why would you say that?
就像赛维鲁斯·亚历山大
Hmm? Oh, Severus Alexander.
那位罗马皇帝
You know, the Roman emperor whose, uh...
因为他被刺杀导致了长达50年的内战
uh, assassination led to 50 years of civil war.
你要这么想的话
If you like.
我想的是你 快点来吧
You know what I like. Hurry up.
乔治
George.
来了
Sorry.
来这儿
Come here.
如果你遇到了问题需要我的帮助
If you were in a situation, if you needed my help...
我现在的确需要你的帮助
I do need your help.
给我挠挠背
Scratch my back.
-不管是什么困难 -别说了
-Wouldn’t matter what it was... -Please stop talking.
我都会来帮你
I would do anything for you.
真的吗
Would you?
真的
Yes.
不管任何事情吗
Anything at all?
对
Yes.
你会撒谎吗
Would you lie?
我不会对你撒谎
Yes. But never to you.
你真好
That’s sweet.
你会欺骗我吗
Would you lie to me?
我不会 除非万不得已的时候
Only if I had to.
-乔治 哪怕是为我杀人你也愿意吗 -愿意
-Would you kill for me, George? -Yes.
-真的吗 -万死不辞
-Would you? -Yes.
我要去睡了
I’m going to bed.
你怎么了
What’s wrong?
没怎么
Nothing.
这周末怎么样
Maybe this weekend?
找个好看点的地方
Someplace nice.
别熬太晚
Don’t stay up too late.
不会吧
The fuck?
等下
Wait, wait, wait.
菲尔怎么了
Phil? Phil?
这周要不要去看个电影
I thought maybe a movie this week.
我礼拜三要出国了 礼拜四回来
Uh, I’m out of the country Wednesday, back Thursday.
那就明天吧
Maybe tomorrow, then.
好
Sure.
最近有什么新上映的电影吗
Is anything playing?
我听说《暗窗》不错
I hear Dark Windowsis good.
《暗窗》
Dark Windows.
没听说过
Don’t know that one.
那要不要去看
Should we see it?
好啊
Love to.
你周三要去哪里
Where are you off to on Wednesday?
黑袋行动
Black bag.
好
Right.
乔治·伍德豪斯
George Woodhouse.
我忘了带工牌了 能给我个临时工牌吗
Forgot my badge. Can I get a temporary?
工牌制度非常重要 伍德豪斯先生
Proper badge protocol is essential, Mr. Woodhouse.
我下次一定不会忘
Never happen again.
-派对很不错 -很高兴你能来参加
-Great party. -Glad you could make it.
我的手指还能动
Fingers still work.
我知道她是个疯婆子
Look, I know she’s crazy as a fucking loon,
但她让我感到快乐
but she makes me happy.
我全部的人生 都奉献给了人民
My whole life, all I’ve done is do for people,
苏珊和我的孩子们
Susan and the kids.
结果大家都恨我
I get nothing but hate for it.
克拉丽莎对此毫无期待
Clarissa expects exactly nothing.
好吧
Okay.
你听说米查姆的事了吗
You’ve heard about Meacham?
他死了 冠状动脉出了问题
He’s dead. Coronary.
-什么时候的事 -昨晚
-When? -Last night.
-我才见过他 -人们总这么说
-I just saw him. -People always say that.
这么年轻就犯心脏病了 你觉得呢
Little young for a heart attack, don’t you think?
是的
Yes.
你知道他在忙什么任务吗
Do you know what he was working on?
不知道
No.
我得去见凯瑟琳
I need to see Kathryn.
施蒂格利茨和她在一起 你可能要
She’s got Stieglitz in there. You might want to...
都到齐了 手上的任务
...all here, the task at hand,
是诉说过去一个半月对你
to fully express those needs and desire to you
的那些需求和渴望
over the last month and a half.
但我见过吗 我是否
But have I seen it? Do I...
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to interrupt.
你的钥匙为什么在我的包里
Why would your key be in my bag?
我在衣柜底部发现了它 我猜是你的
Found it on the closet floor and thought it was yours.
它们长得都一样
They all look alike.
我的包在桌子上
My bag’s by the desk.
下午一点前 钥匙还给我
I need my key back by 1:00.
两分钟
Two minutes.
你没事吧
You okay?
我听说了米查姆的事
I just heard about Meacham.
太可怕了
Terrible.
还有其他消息吗
Anything else?
没了
No.
如果你不介意 回家的路上给自己买点吃的
Grab yourself something on the way home, if you don’t mind.
我可能要去湖边
I might stop off at the lake.
苏黎世湖
Zurich?
47.3701 北
47.3701 north,
8.5411 东
8.5411 east.
不好意思 我迟到了
Sorry. Running behind.
没事
Mm-hmm.
我们能晚几分钟开始吗
Can you go a few minutes late?
访谈不超过45分钟 我就无法解除命令
If we don’t do 45, I can’t clear the mandate.
那就2点6分开始
Uh, I make that 2:06.
好吧
Fine.
我仍然时睡时醒
Uh, sleep remains inconsistent.
我服用了2.5至3毫克劳拉西泮
I take two-point-five to three milligrams of lorazepam,
晚上8点服用了一次 11点又服用了一次
the first at 8:00, the second at 11:00
夜间做噩梦后
and the third in the night.
又服用了一次
After the first nightmare.
还是每晚做噩梦吗
You’re still having them every night?
是的
Yes.
草药能帮助我入睡
Um... the herbal sleep aids
但让我眩晕无力 所以我停用了
leave me groggy, so I-I discontinued,
几乎隔天吃一次唑吡坦
and zolpidem is at most an every-other-day option.
连续两天 每天超过0.5毫克
More than point-five milligrams two days in a row
第二天早上就莫名窝火
produces unmotivated rage the next morning.
如果连续服用三天或以上
And three or more days in a row...
情况会变得更遭
...things get even uglier.
什么
What?
我觉得 你上报得很谨慎
I just... I-I think that’s an extremely careful report.
为什么这么说
How so?
劳拉西泮3毫克或以下
Uh, lorazepam three milligrams or below,
唑吡坦每月20毫克以下
zolpidem below 20 milligrams per month,
还有草药叫南非醉茄是吧
and the herbal, that’s... that’s ashwagandha, right?
-是的 -好的
-Yes. -Yeah. Yeah.
我觉得这些剂量
I think those amounts and dosages
不用上报
are just under my reporting requirements.
你也清楚
And you know that.
你觉得我在蒙你 为了不进入
And you feel it’s duplicitous for me to want to avoid
心理服务上报流程
involvement in psych services reporting chains?
我说过了 我认为你很谨慎
As I said, I-I think it’s careful.
我是这里任务中心的主管 我当然得谨慎了
I’m the head of sig ops; of course I’m careful.
这不是我们在此的目的
Well, that’s not the goal in here.
目的是服从命令
The goal is to satisfy the mandate
这样我才能回去工作
so I can get back to work.
你为什么要跟拉姆罗德·吉米·斯托克斯上床
Why on earth are you sleeping with Ramrod Jimmy Stokes?
-他配不上你 -我们专业点
-He’s beneath you. -Let’s keep this professional.
专业点
Professional?
你跑到我家来
You came to my home.
喝了酒 吃了饭 高谈阔论你的性生活
You drank, you ate, you talked about your sex life.
这算哪门子专业
What in God’s name is professional about that?
也许那个叫观察性访视
Maybe it was an observational visit.
我一直都看在眼里
I’ve had it up to my eyeballs
我被我周围的每一个人监视
being watched by every single person around me.
哦是的 无论如何 把那个记下来
Oh, yes, by all means, write that one down.
偏执多疑
Paranoid ideations.
让上面再给我下6个月的命令
Buy me another mandatory six months.
你知道吗 我总能知道你何时要来
You know, I always know when you’re arriving.
你来之前 我就能感受到你的杀气
Because the aroma of hostility wafts in ahead of you.
你头一回不那么无聊了
Oh, well, that’s the first interesting thing you’ve said.
你和乔治怎么样了
How are things with George?
那天 亚瑟·施蒂格利茨跟我说
The other day, Arthur Stieglitz told me
我对婚姻的投入是我的职业弱点
that my devotion to my marriage is my professional weakness.
我对乔治的爱是我的致命伤
That my feelings for George are a gaping wound
任何人都能利用他来伤害我
through which any idiot can attack me.
他跟我说 我想要的太多 不可能什么都得到
He told me I want too much and that I cannot have it all.
我要顶替他的工作了
I’m going to have his job.
你看着吧
You watch.
他说的对吗
Is he right?
如果这种情况出现
If a situation presents itself,
你会选择婚姻 放弃其他吗
would you choose your marriage over everything else?
我很珍视忠诚
I value loyalty.
对什么的忠诚
To what?
你原来是天主教徒 对吧
You were raised Catholic, weren’t you?
你说什么
Hmm? Mm.
无所谓 你曾经是
Never mind. You were.
在布莱克浦的圣安东尼读了12年书
12 years at St. Anthony’s in Blackpool.
好吧 他们没跟你说过你曾经是个坏学生吗
Yeah. Did they tell you you were a bad little girl?
所以你才喜欢色情作品
Oh, is that why you like erotica?
因为这很叛逆 和规则对着干
Because it’s naughty. It’s against the rules.
这些作品说了你不敢说的话
Says everything you can’t.
哦 我猜你还喜欢听挑逗的话
Yeah. Oh, I bet you go for dirty talk, too.
我会上报 说你完成了心理访视
I’ll report you completed the session.
-你可以走了 -为什么
-You can go. -Why?
你情况好转
This is just getting good.
佐伊·沃恩 北方来的好天主教女
Zoe Vaughan, nice Catholic girl from the North,
只想帮助他人
just wants to help people,
谈论他人的问题
wants to talk about their problems.
为什么是我俩
Come on. Why us?
我对人感到好奇
I’m curious about people.
而现在 我对你感到好奇
And right now, I’m curious about you.
唑吡坦
Zolpidem.
服用三天后 你说“情况会变得更遭”
After three days, you said "things get even uglier."
-我有情绪了 -什么情绪
-I get moods. -What kind of moods?
-黑暗情绪 -自杀情绪
-Dark. -Suicidal?
不是
No.
我焦虑了
Panicked.
为钱感到焦虑
Over money still?
虽然所有的证据都指向另一方
Despite all evidence to the contrary?
我不会像我妈一样
Well, I’ll not end up like my mother.
你头一回不那么无聊了
That’s the first interesting thing you’ve said.
如果按计划投放死危病毒
If Severus is deployed as intended,
成千上万的无辜百姓会丧命
thousands of innocent people will die.
你打算什么时候给我测个谎 乔治
When are you gonna poly me, George?
该死
Shit.
抱歉
Sorry.
我知道我不该闯进来
I know I’m intruding.
但发生了我们日常上报情况
A situation’s come up that I think falls
以外的事件
outside our usual reporting parameters.
如果你愿意 我们可以使用涉敏信息隔离设施
If you prefer, we could use a SCIF.
接着说
Go on.
-奇怪了 -检测到了前导码
-It’s awkward. -Preamble noted.
我们的金融人员正在配合英国税务海关总署行动
Our financial people have been working with HMRC,
在避税国家里清查银行
running a sweep of banks in tax haven countries.
他们例行公事地对大额账户
They routinely run ID scrapes past us
进行身份核查
for non-insignificant balances,
以免我们中有人
in case one of our persona IDs is used
开了一个离岸账户
to open an offshore account.
从来没有
Never once has been.
这次 他们查到了一个人
This time, they got a hit.
假名是什么
What’s the fake name?
玛格丽特·兰福德
"Margaret Langford."
出生日期和姓名与组织生成的护照匹配
DOB and name match an SIS-generated passport
从2008年起
from 2008.
-谁注册的 -09年洗白的身份
-Who registered it? -Scrubbed in ’09.
在老案子的卷宗里查名字和出生日期
Search old case files for the name and date of birth.
也都洗掉了 她在2009年后就像不存在了
Also scrubbed. She’s a nonentity post-2009.
-指纹呢 -没有匹配的
-Thumbprint? -None required.
那就是在二阶段之前
It was just before Phase II.
账户在哪家银行
What bank holds the account?
亚洲信托资本
Asia Trust & Capital.
稳健之选 我也会选这家
Obscure choice. It’s what I would’ve picked.
银行外有监控摄像头面部识别
Facial rec on surveillance cams outside the bank
开户时间
the day the account was opened.
那是8个月以前了 缅甸的非合作社
That was eight months ago, and Myanmar’s non-co-op.
有的时候如果你知道该问谁的话
Sometimes if you know who to ask...
如果是在缅甸 我们是怎么查到账户的呢
If it’s Myanmar, how do we know about the account at all?
有人心惊胆战 转走了钱
Well, somebody got jumpy and transferred the money
在政变前夕抽身了
out of there when it looked like there’d be another coup.
我们收到了来自新银行的环球银行金融电信协会线索
We got a hit on the incoming SWIFT at the new bank.
-在哪 -瑞士
-Where? -Raffenkalt/Suisse AG.
苏黎世
Zurich.
Zurich?
这说明什么了
That mean something?
账户里有多少钱
How much is in the account?
七百万
Seven million.
英镑
Pounds.
我们的一个人偷了个假身份
So one of our people stole a straw man identity
收取了700万英镑
and has been paid seven million pounds under it.
是的
Yes.
什么
What?
在2008年SIGINT行动结束前
"Margaret Langford" was used a handful of times
玛格丽特·兰福德 这个名字用了好多次了
by a SIGINT op in 2008 before discontinuance.
谁用的
Used by whom?
你的妻子
Your wife.
我知道了
I see.
我明白了
就像我说的 我觉得这是
As I said, I thought this was
超出我们正常的报告情况
outside our normal reporting parameters.
-还有谁知道 -没人了
-Who else knows? -No one.
把这交给我吧 拜托了
Leave it with me, please.
詹姆斯
James.
这笔钱是分期存的还是一次性存入
Was the money deposited in increments or lump sum?
一次性转入
Lump sum.
有人卖出了一些非常昂贵的东西
Someone sold something extremely valuable.
爱丽丝
Alice?
爱丽丝 你在吗
Alice, are you here?
爱丽丝
Alice?
理查德 你在做什么
Richard, what are you doing?!
什么 我只是打开门
What? I just opened the door.
-莫妮卡去哪了 -她去找人帮忙了
-Where’s Monica? -She’s gone to get help.
你应该听听你自己在说什么
You should’ve heard yourself.
我讨厌鸟 把手电筒给我
I hate birds. Give me the torch.
我喜欢手电
I like the torch.
用你的手机吧
Use your phone.
鳟鱼
Trout?
-白鳟鱼 -噢
-Vendace. -Oh.
-一直留着呢 -美味
-Been saving it. -Delicious.
是不是很难捕到
Is it a difficult catch?
几乎不可能
Next to impossible.
你什么时候回来
When will you be back?
噢 明天 稍晚时候
Oh, tomorrow, late.
不用等我了
Don’t wait up.
我讨厌两地相隔
I hate the distance.
没事 我们都习惯了
Well, we’re pretty good at it.
感觉很奇怪
It seems grotesque.
这份工作对人太苛刻了
What’s asked of a person.
该死的
Oh, shit.
一路顺风
Bon voyage.
旅途愉快
Or Gute Reise.
爱你
Love you.
哦 这爱情啊
♪ To love, to love, to love ♪
该死的
Shit.
我们何其有幸
♪ Oh, how lucky we are... ♪
怎么回事 乔治
What the fuck, George?!
我有麻烦了吗
Am I in trouble?
完全没有
Not at all.
所以到底怎么了
So what’s up, man?
我理解 你和弗雷迪还在一起
I understand, uh, you and Freddie are still together.
是的
Yeah.
这难道不会有些尴尬吗
Isn’t that a bit awkward?
因为我用牛排刀把他的手钉在桌子上了
Because I pinned his hand to the table with a steak knife?
很难不想起
That comes to mind.
他原谅了我 我也原谅他
He forgave me. I forgave him.
你知道吗 这件事恰好把我们扯平了
You know? The hand thing kind of evened us out.
好的
Okay.
乔治 今晚11点来我公寓
George, you come to my apartment at 11:00 at night
和我聊聊我的感情问题
asking about my relationship.
我都不感觉惊讶 我甚至都不确定自己会拒绝
I’m not shocked, and I’m not even sure I’m saying no,
但你真的要这么做吗
but are you actually doing this?
噢不
Uh, no.
那你想要什么
Then what do you want?
你在321大楼有国防部的监控录像
You have MOD imagery oversight in Building 321
64只眼睛中的一只
on one of the 64 eyes.
有那么一瞬间 我还当你是人
For a minute there, I thought you were human.
我明天早上需要一个简短的键孔重定向
I need a brief Keyhole redirect tomorrow morning,
它需要注销和清除记录
and it needs to be un-logged and unrecorded.
我觉得不行
I don’t even think that’s possible.
可以的
It is.
在交接的时候有一个短暂的空档
There are brief periods between satlink handovers
让卫星可以转接给其他目标
where a satellite could be used for another purpose
不会被发觉
without detection.
我在拉特克利夫做过
I’ve done it, in Ratcliffe.
但这次需要是非官方的
But this one has to be unofficial.
我为什么要做这种事
Why would I do something like that?
我会觉得我欠你个人情
I would consider myself in your debt.
那对我有什么好处
What does that get me?
隐私
Privacy.
我个人从未发现过
I have personally never found
摇头丸或许还 尚可容忍
ecstasy use to be a compromising factor.
但如果有多个性伴侣
But combined with multiple sexual partners...
对于弗雷迪而言 这就很成问题了
...it would be of issue, to Freddie.
他的不忠是一回事 但你
His infidelity is one thing, but yours...
弗雷迪在这方面是很老派的
Freddie’s old-fashioned.
-你这个混蛋 -这很重要
-You’re a bastard. -It’s important.
如果我爱他呢
What if I love him?
那你就会帮我了
Then you’ll help me.
但这对你有影响吗
But does that matter to you?
你知道的 你还有人性的那部分
You know, the human part.
你会在意吗
Does that... do you care about that?
我应该和谁在一起
Who am I supposed to be with?
告诉我
Tell me.
抱歉 额 这感觉是一种狡辩
Sorry, uh, it seemed rhetorical.
我不能在外面找人约会
I can’t date outside.
他们不会理解
They don’t understand.
我也不能和圈内人在一起 因为我们都是该死的骗子
And I can’t date inside because we’re all fucking liars.
你理解的 专业的事情
You know, professional ones
一个多完美的借口啊
with a perfect excuse every time.
「那么 你上周在哪呢」
"Well, where were you last week?"
「黑袋」
"Black bag."
「周五你做什么」 「黑袋」
"What did you do on Friday?" "Black bag."
当你可以对一切事情撒谎的时候
When you can lie about everything,
当你可以否认一切的时候
when you can deny everything,
那你还能说真话吗
how do you tell the truth about anything?
这是怎么运行的
How does that work?
这怎么可能维持下去呢
How can that possibly work?
我不知道
I don’t know.
但你确实知道
But you do know.
你知道因为这对你管用
You do know because it works for you.
还有你们是该死的完美情侣
And you’re the perfect fucking couple,
每个人都知道 所以告诉我吧
and everyone knows it, so tell me.
告诉我该怎么做
Tell me how it works.
明早六点半
6:30 a.m. tomorrow.
安全起见 提前几分钟
A few minutes early to be safe.
有安全地点吗
Is there a secure view site?
在主64号监控节点处有个封闭涉敏信息隔离设施
There’s a lookdown SCIF off the main 64.
很好
Good.
谢谢你的酒
Thank you for the wine.
你不用这么威胁我帮你办事
You didn’t have to come at me like that, you know.
反正我肯定会帮你的
I would’ve done it for you anyway.
准备好叛国了吗
Ready for some treason?
这不好笑
That isn’t funny.
当然好笑
Sure it is.
要看哪个地方
Where are we looking?
北纬47.3701度
47.3701 north,
东经8.5411度
8.5411 east.
好 只有一个合适的选择
Okay. There’s only one good option there.
位于938英里高空强大的军事星卫星
Very masculine Milstar satellite up at 938 miles.
这条线很少使用 就位于列支敦士登上空
Ops arc isn’t used much. It’s over Liechtenstein.
就是那个 第二排 右数第三个
It’s that one. Second row down, third from the right.
即将切换到高分四号
About to hand off to a Gaofen-4.
还有多长时间
How long will we have?
三分二十秒
Three minutes, 20 seconds.
他有失误的时候吗
Does he miss anything?
少校吗 从未有过
The major? Never once.
准备好了吗
Ready?
-等等 -乔治
-Wait. -George.
不行 乔治 我快暴露了 到底做不做
No, George, I’m naked out here. Are we doing this or not?
行动
Go.
切换
Handoff.
苏黎世 苏黎世怎么了
Zurich? What the hell’s in Zurich?
放大
Move in.
放大 坐标不变
Closer. Same coordinates.
放大
Closer.
长椅不错 可以了吗
Nice bench. Are we done?
等等
Wait.
他们迟到了
They’re late.
你真是个不省心的丈夫 乔治
You are one naughty husband, George.
你之前问我在这行里
You asked how it works.
该怎么同伴侣生活下去
To be with someone in this business.
这就是答案
This is how.
你们各自都清楚自己的任务和职责
You each know what you know, and you know what you’ll do,
但你们不会对某类事深究下去
and you never discuss certain things again.
我盯着她 我猜她也盯着我
I watch her. I assume she watches me.
要是她遇到麻烦了 哪怕是她自找的
If she’s in trouble, even of her own making,
我也会尽一切可能帮她脱身
I will do everything in my power to extricate her.
不会有任何顾虑
No matter what that means.
你明白吗
You understand?
天呐 太美好了
My God, that’s so hot.
就要这么做
That’s how it works.
这是唯一的办法
It’s the only way.
还能拉近些吗
Can you get any closer?
人脸识别
Facial rec?
什么都没有吗
Nothing?
再等一下
Give it a minute.
库里科夫
Kulikov.
-还有一分钟 -等等
-One minute. -Hang on.
试试这个
Trying something.
这是一种唇语识别技术
It’s a lipreading AI.
目前还是测试版
Still in beta.
声音传来了
Audio coming.
钱已经到位了
The money’s in place.
做好你的任务 我就给你
Do your fucking job, and I’ll release.
她不是卖方 她是买方
She isn’t selling. She’s buying.
情况很复杂
It’s a complicated situation.
14秒
14 seconds.
你得好好想想
You need to think about it.
-把画面找回来 -好 在试了
-Get them back. -Yeah, trying.
-我必须让画面消失一下 -快找回来
-I’ve got to let them go. -Get them back!
我必须让画面消失一下
I’ve got to let them go!
-该死 -怎么了
-Shit. -What?
没有反应
It’s not responding.
-快解决掉 -我不知道该怎么
-Get rid of it. -I don’t know what...
我在试了 我
I’m trying. I...
为什么
Why the...
见鬼
Shit!
他看到了吗
Did he see?
我不知道 你录下来了吗
I don’t know. Did you record?
这会自动记录
It’s automatic.
去根文件中删掉
Go into the root files and delete.
包括按键记录也删掉
Keystroke logs, too.
好 希望你得到你想要的了
Yeah, well, I hope you got what you wanted.
要是我完蛋了 你也逃不掉
If I’m going down, you’re coming with me.
这句话我记下了
I’ll keep that in mind.
我不明白
I don’t understand.
哪部分
Which part?
整件事
All of it.
詹姆斯 拜托 你多大了
James, come on. How old are you?
过来
Come over here.
什么
What?
过来
Come over here.
这不是我来的目的
It’s not that kind of visit.
那是什么目的
What kind of visit is it, then?
我这次来是想说我们不该再见面了
The kind where I say we’re not seeing each other anymore.
为什么不能再见了
And why not again?
因为我不想
Because I don’t want to.
那我们之前在那边的小聚算什么
What about the times we had our little sessions, over there?
-你那时就愿意 -对
-You wanted to then. -Yeah.
但我现在不想了
And now I don’t.
看到没 这不合常规
You see, this isn’t normal.
你处理事情的这种方式 我想要你知道
The way you’re doing this, just so you know.
我们在这里做的事
And what we did in here...
都不合常规
None of this is normal.
是不正常
No, it isn’t.
你跟你的病人一样不正常
You’re as sick as your patients.
可能吧
Possibly.
但没有哪条法律规定
But there’s no law that says
治疗师不能有自己的问题
that therapists can’t have issues of their own.
-你在跟别人约会吗 -是
-Are you seeing someone else? -Yes.
见鬼 你真冷酷
Fuck me, you’re cold.
对 有一点
Yeah, a bit.
是啊 你甚至连自己是否冷漠都毫不在乎
Yeah, you’re even cold about whether or not you’re cold.
我会永久停止对你的治疗
I’m gonna clear your mandate permanently.
我会让心理服务部门向你推荐其他精神科医生
I’ll tell psych services to recommend a psychiatrist
处理你未来可能需要的处方治疗问题
for any prescriptive issues you might have in the future.
我告诉过你一些事情
I told you things.
你的所有想法和感受都是保密的
All your thoughts and feelings are confidential.
咱们的关系可以
Our relationship can just...
行了 我不在乎咱们有过什么关系
Yeah, I don’t give a shit about the relationship.
我翻篇了 我还有其他事情要做
I’m over it. I got something else on the side, too.
我告诉过你些任务上的事
I told you operational things.
你是指死危病毒吗
Are you referring to Severus?
我当时已经烂醉如泥了
I was drunk as hell.
你说过的任何有关死危病毒的事也会保密
Anything you told me regarding Severus is also privileged.
很好
That’s great.
因为不得不杀你也会是件麻烦事
’Cause it’d be a real drag to have to kill you.
我从来欣赏不了这种幽默
I’ve never appreciated that sort of humor.
对我也从未喜欢过你这一点
Yeah, and I never liked that about you either.
你知道你能在这里放什么吗
You know what you could use in here?
一个目光会跟随着你的天鹅绒耶稣像
A velvet Jesus with eyes that follow you.
你想要这种 不是吗
You’d like that, wouldn’t you?
有工作找我
It’s duty desk.
接吧
Go ahead.
谢谢 妈妈
Thanks, Mom.
怎么了
Yes?
什么时候
When?
多久了
How long?
我马上过去
I’ll be right there.
我要走了
I got to go.
我有些东西在你那里
I left some things at your place.
他们都放在标有你名字的袋子里 就在桌子上
They’re in a pouch at the desk under your name.
我今早放上去的
I left it there this morning.
这真是我最好的分手经历
This is the best breakup I ever had.
说真的 我乐在其中
Seriously, I enjoyed myself.
保重 佐伊
Take care, Zoe.
你真他妈了不起
You’re a fucking piece of work.
少校来电
The major called.
我们有安全漏洞了
We’ve got a breach.
是我 别搞我 拜托
It’s me. Don’t be a dick. Come on.
上帝啊
Jesus.
你一定想知道这个
You’ll want to know about this.
哦不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
好了
All right.
我们开始吧
Let’s get started.
查尔兹女士 请吧
Ms. Childs, would you please?
好的 这是瓦迪木·帕夫留克
Okay, so this is Vadim Pavlichuk,
持不同政见的俄罗斯将军
the dissident Russian general under house arrest
过去六个月被软禁在列支敦士登
in Liechtenstein for the past six months.
据悉帕夫留克一直在使用流亡军国主义分子创建的网络
Pavlichuk’s been known to be working with a network
由于俄罗斯对于战争管理不善
of exiled militarists for the overthrow of the Russian regime
这些军国主义分子企图推翻其政权
due to its mismanagement of the war.
自从他抵达后 我们已经对这所房子监视了24小时
We’ve had the house on lockdown for 24 hours since he arrived.
如果帕夫留克采取行动 我们会第一时间知道
If Pavlichuk made a move, we wanted to know first.
他现在已经采取行动了
He has now made a move.
这些是中欧时间早上6点31分
These are the heat signatures
房子里的热信号
in the house at 6:31 a.m. Central European Time.
七个人的信号
Seven unique sigs.
然后在一次例行的卫星链路交接中
We then lost signal with the house
我们失去了信号 时间大约持续了
during a routine satlink handover for about...
-3分20秒 -谢谢
-Three minutes, 20 seconds. -Thank you.
3分20秒
Three minutes, 20 seconds.
当我们在6:35恢复信号并再次运行热成像时
When we regained signal and ran thermals again at 6:35,
这就是我们所看到的
this is what we see.
现在只有五个信号了
There are now only five.
在过去的两个小时里
For the last two hours,
我们一直在核对所有人的个人标识
we’ve been accounting for all the individual sigs.
我们拍到了五个人进出的记录
We got all five as they came and went.
但都不是帕夫留克
None of them were Pavlichuk.
所以这混蛋跑了
So the son of a bitch is out, hmm?
怎么跑的
How could that happen?
他怎么知道卫星链路交接的确切时间
How would he know the exact timing of a satlink handover?
嗯 他妈的太确切了
Well, fucking exactly.
除非这里有人告诉他 否则他怎么知道
How could he know unless someone here told him?
我们一没盯着 他就跑了
We look away, he takes off.
这是一次预谋行动
It was an operation.
非常准确
Very precise.
不是吗
Hmm?
这里有个陌生人
There is a stranger in our house.
他离开后 我们接到帕夫留克了吗
Have we picked up Pavlichuk since he left?
他没问题
He’s good.
他蜷缩在某辆黑色面包车里
He’s hunched over in a black van somewhere,
准备去干坏事
off to malefact.
呃 好吧 我们的假设是
Uh, well, our assumption is
他的得力助手 前副官安德烈·库里科夫
that his right-hand former lieutenant Andrei Kulikov
现在正在去接他的路上
is en route to pick him up now.
他们的意图尚不清楚
Their intentions are unclear.
今早 库里科夫在苏黎世与一个不知名的人士会面
Kulikov had a meeting with an unknown party in Zurich
我们正在等待相关的影像资料
this morning, so we’re waiting on visuals for that.
嗯嗯 继续
Mm-hmm. Keep at it.
我们应该
Should we...
我们应该通知CIA吗
Should we notify CIA?
哦 去他妈的CIA
Oh, fuck them.
我受够了被当作情报的取款机
I’m sick of being treated like an ATM for intel.
而且我当然也不会让他们看我们出丑
And I’m certainly not showing them our dirty linens.
如果这里有叛徒
If there’s a traitor in the house,
我想在CIA查到之前 查出是谁
I want to know who it is before they do.
这事只能在这里说
This stays in the room.
你说少校 呃
You said the major was, uh...
知道重新定向吗
...aware of the redirect?
是的 我收到了警报并给他打了电话
Yes. I got a signal alert and called him.
-他已经知道了 -嗯
-He already knew. -Hmm.
把他重新分配到巴哈马的某个好地方
Have him reassigned... somewhere lovely, the Bahamas.
告诉他这是升职 立即生效
Tell him it’s a promotion, effective immediately.
他明天就去
He travels tomorrow.
请问 从战略上讲
Can I ask, strategically,
我们为什么在乎帕夫留克跑了
why do we care that Pavlichuk is out?
S-6级别以下 请回避
S-6 and below, please clear.
死危病毒
Severus.
我们相信帕夫留克已经得到了一份实体副本
We believe Pavlichuk has been given a physical copy.
这就是我们监视他的原因
That’s why we watched him.
如果库里科夫设法让他带着病毒回到莫斯科
If Kulikov manages to get him back into Moscow with it,
那就
well...
斯摩尔斯先生 请给我们的同事解释一下
Mr. Smalls, educate our colleagues.
死危病毒是我们与NSA一起开发的
Severus is a Stuxnet polymorph
多晶型蠕虫病毒
we developed with NSA.
它必须通过物理方式
It has to be physically introduced
进入核反应堆以通过气隙
to a nuclear reactor to get past an air gap.
但它一旦进入 就可以瞄准并熔化反应堆堆芯
But once it’s in, it can target and melt down the reactor core.
这是美国网络司令部的行动
It was a CYBERCOM op.
我们为什么要做那个东西
Why the fuck would we make that?
理论上做的出 跟有能力做的出还是有区别的
Theoreticals. Capabilities.
它不应该离开那栋大楼
It shouldn’t have left the building.
我们意识到 如果我们能对他们动手
And we realized, if we can do it to them,
-一旦那玩意儿流到外面 -他们可以对我们动手
-once the thing is out there... -They can do it to us.
是个好主意
It was a good idea.
嗯
Hmm?
灾难将导致政治混乱
A meltdown would cause political havoc.
对于一个卷入无休止战争的敌人
For an enemy involved in an endless war
以及一个摇摇欲坠的政府来说
and a teetering government,
他们会用铁轨把亲爱的领袖赶出莫斯科
they’d run dear leader out of Moscow on a rail.
我们就能一劳永逸地摆脱这个刺头了
We’d be rid of the prick once and for all.
我们没有这样做
We didn’t do it...
但这真他妈是个好主意
...but it was a damn good idea.
看来这里有人也有同样的感觉
It would appear someone here felt the same way.
嗯嗯 重新定向监视视线
Mm-hmm. And redirected the eye
这样帕夫留克就可以带着驱动器逃跑了
so Pavlichuk could escape with the drive.
他现在正在前往俄罗斯的路上 以引发一场灾难
He’s on his way to Russia now to initiate a meltdown,
这他妈将是我们的错
and it’ll be our goddamn fault!
找到泄漏点
Find the leak.
不管用什么方法
Methods won’t be questioned.
这下可不妙
This can’t be good.
的确
It isn’t.
乔治命令重新定向
George ordered the redirect.
我帮助他做到了
I helped him do it.
谢谢
Thanks.
凯瑟琳
Kathryn.
上帝啊 弗雷迪
Jesus, Freddie.
有时间吗
Got a minute?
还有其他人知道吗
Does anyone else know?
没有
No.
-你能信任克拉丽莎吗 -不是很信任
-Can you trust Clarissa? -Not particularly.
-我是说 她不会说出去 -我觉得可以
-To keep it to herself, I mean. -I think so.
她喜欢乔治 她很担心
She’s fond of George. She’s concerned.
无论他在进行什么行动 他都处于危险的境地
Whatever operation he’s running, he’s in a very leaky boat.
如果帕夫留克回到俄罗斯 那就看他自己了
If Pavlichuk gets back to Russia, it’s on him.
他已经活了35年
He’d get 35 years.
你能做些什么吗
Is there anything you can do?
苏黎世怎么样
How was Zurich?
毫无意义 他一无所有
It was pointless. He had nothing.
我不知道自己为什么去那里
I don’t know why I was there.
我花了一整天的时间在FIS追逐冈瑟
I spent the rest of the day chasing down Gunther at FIS,
但他一无是处
but he was useless.
你知道为什么乔治会监视你吗
Do you have any idea why George would be watching you?
毫无头绪
None whatsoever.
好吧
All right.
你早上准备好
You be ready in the morning.
我需要一个晚上来考虑
I need a night to think.
好
Okay.
只有你和我
Just you and me.
是吗
Yes?
当然
Of course.
我肯定自己已经被陷害了
I believe I’ve been set up.
我想我也是
I think I have been, too.
被弗雷迪 被所有人
By Freddie, of all people.
为什么
Why?
嗯 他在耍我
Well, he’s playing me.
他认为我会采取行动保护你
He thinks I’ll take action to protect you.
他说得对
And he’s right.
我会为你杀人 乔治
I will kill for you, George.
你知道的
You know that.
弗雷迪偷了死危病毒
Freddie stole Severus.
啊 也许是 也许不是
Ah, maybe, maybe not.
这已经不是真的了 不是吗
It’s not really about that anymore, is it?
不知为什么
Somehow it’s...
这是关于我们的
...it’s about us.
有一个计划
There’s a plan.
还有一个对策
And a counterplan.
一个利用你接近我，另一个利用我来接近你
One is using you to get to me, the other, me to get to you.
那么，我们打算怎么应对
Well, what are we going to do about that?
扰乱他们
Disrupt.
他们的所有计划
All of it.
逼他主动就范
Bait someone into an overreaction.
会不会又出现一些新麻烦需要收拾
Will there be another mess to clean up?
做对了才会有
Only if we do it right.
你要是早点打电话就好了 我连钓具都没有
Wish you’d called sooner. I didn’t really have any gear.
先上船吧
Hop in.
钓鱼我不在行
Fishing’s not really my thing.
你只需要有些耐心
Patience. All you need.
我们不需要花太久
We’ll be back in plenty of time.
这里更适合思考
It’s easier to think out here.
我需要一些帮助
I need something.
需要追踪安德烈·库里科夫 最后位置在苏黎世
Geofencing on Andrei Kulikov. Last known is Zurich.
我要对他的手机进行动态追踪
I want a moving trace on his cell,
不能留下记录
and I want it to be un-logged.
我可不想为了你们两个疯子住监狱
I’m not going to prison for you psychos.
哦 你现在才说这个是不是有点晚了
Oh, you’re too far in to worry about that now,
你不觉得吗
don’t you think?
真他妈的天生一对
Fucking made for each other.
我想安排几场测谎
I’d like to set up a series of polygraphs.
今天
Today.
在沃克斯豪尔的房间
The usual room at Vauxhall.
你打算测谁
Who did you have in mind?
弗雷迪·斯莫尔斯
Freddie Smalls.
克拉丽莎·杜博斯
Clarissa Dubose.
佐伊·沃恩博士
Dr. Zoe Vaughan.
怎么还有她
Why her?
弗雷迪过去八个月每周见她两次
Freddie saw her twice a week for the past eight months.
有重大嫌疑
Leakage.
我也见过她
And I’ve seen her, too.
我知道 那把你自己也加上吧
I know. Put yourself down as well.
公正公开
Transparency.
还有其他人吗
Anyone else?
暂时没有
Not for the moment.
那么 关于瑞士银行的问题
So, that Swiss banking issue.
我一直想跟你跟进一下
I’d been meaning to follow up with you.
当然人们会想到
Of course one’s mind
这可能和死危病毒有关
goes to a possible Severus connection.
我也想到过
That had occurred to me.
是么
Had it?
看起来确实有关联
It would appear to be linked.
你跟别人分享过你的怀疑吗
Have you shared your suspicions with anyone else?
当然没有
Of course not.
但你依然肯定
But you still feel certain of the identity
开通离岸账户的人是谁吗
of the person who opened the offshore account?
我不确定
No.
不确定 问题就在这里
No, that’s the thing.
这就是为什么我一直想跟你跟进
That’s why I’d been meaning to follow up with you.
哦
Oh.
「玛格丽特·兰福德」
"Margaret Langford."
凯瑟琳在08年使用的护照名字
The passport name that Kathryn used in ’08.
结果发现系统出了点问题
Turns out there was some sort of glitch.
它被系统反复回收
It was repeatedly recycled by the system,
在SIS内部流传了十年
passed around SIS for a decade.
至少被使用了十几次
There’s at least a dozen uses.
四五十条边境记录
40 or 50 border records.
你居然漏掉了这个 有点奇怪
Seems odd you’d miss that.
是的
Yes.
是啊 我恨死自己了
Yeah, I’m kicking myself.
这太马虎了
It was sloppy.
重点是
The point is...
可能是任何人
it could’ve been anyone.
我们不再盯着凯瑟琳了
We’re no longer looking at Kathryn.
「我们」吗
"We"?
你和我
You and me.
喔喔我该做什么
Whoa, whoa! Wh-What do I do?
坐壁上观
Let him run for a minute.
给艾玛的美式咖啡
Americano for Emma.
谢谢
Thank you.
适时信号区域锁定 这是追踪登录
Live cell zone lock. That’s the trace log-in.
他在移动
He’s moving.
这是什么，我的生日礼物吗
What is this, my birthday?
你能尽快批准吗
Can you get it approved quickly?
为了防止死危病毒扩散么
To keep Severus from getting out?
越快越好
Speed of light.
卖我个面子
I’ll owe you.
真的么 这跟你有什么关系
Really, why do you care?
这是私人计划
It’s a private agenda.
说了跟没说一样
That’s not really an answer.
我们的人被渗透了
One of our people is compromised.
无人机打击会重置一切
Drone strike resets everything.
只是库利科夫，还是我要连带其他人一起干掉
Just Kulikov or am I taking anybody else out with him?
这简直是天降大礼
It’s a gift from fucking heaven.
-你们要不要 -要 我们要
-Do you want it or not? -Yes, we want it.
我只是在了解全局
I’m just getting my arms around the global.
他接下来三个小时会在波兰境内移动
He’s traveling across Poland for the next three hours.
时不我待
Don’t wait.
您的活造料理
This is ikizukuri.
谢谢 吉米
Thank you, Jimmy.
你想要什么 嗯
What do you want? Hmm?
活造料理在英国是违法的
Ikizukuri is illegal in the U.K.
如果你不介意 我更喜欢一个人吃
If you don’t mind, I prefer to eat alone.
你知道 我无法洞察一切
You know, I can’t see all the corners,
但是你瞒不了我
but I can tell the shape.
而这个 都是你的
And this, all yours.
你到底在说什么
What could you possibly be talking about?
哦 别装了
Oh, please.
停止你的行动
Your operation stops.
马上
Right now.
呃
Mm.
你有点迟了
You’re a little late for that.
-是吗 -嗯
-Yeah? -Mm.
回去后去要中情局的无人机日志
Ask for the CIA drone logs when you get back.
一次泄漏会害死多少人
How many would a meltdown have killed?
一万 两万
10,000? 20,000?
你做了什么
What did you do?
嗯
Hmm?
取消你的行动
Canceled your op.
你这个愚蠢的混蛋
You stupid son of a bitch.
你无法想象你刚刚造成的破坏
You cannot imagine the damage you just did.
嗯
Mm?
现在 我不知道你找了谁帮忙
Now, I don’t know who you enlisted to help,
但乔治已经盯上这件事了
but George has got his teeth in it now.
-嗯 -你难道没有见过
-Mm. -Have you seen him
他死咬着不放的样子吗
when his jaws lock on something?
你就算把自己撕碎 他也不会放过你
You’ll rip yourself apart before he’ll let go.
吃吧
Eat up.
这件事最终会以某人被灭口收场
This ends with someone in the boot of a car.
如果我们能快点的话
If we could make this quick.
-开始吗 -请便
-Shall we? -Be my guest.
今天是星期五吗
Is today Friday?
是的
Yes.
你居住在英国吗
Do you reside in the United Kingdom?
是的
Yes.
弗雷德里克·艾伦·斯莫尔斯是你的真实合法名字吗
Is Frederick Alan Smalls your true legal name?
是的
Yes.
你今天早上自慰了吗
Did you masturbate this morning?
哦 很好
Oh, good.
尴尬的私人问题来得真早
The embarrassing personal questions start early.
请尽可能回答是或否
Yes or no whenever possible, please.
你知道 我一直很期待这个
You know, I’ve been looking forward to this.
你今天早上自慰了吗
Did you masturbate this morning?
没有
No.
没时间
Didn’t have time.
你是坐着的吗
Are you sitting down?
是的
Yes.
这个房间的灯是开着的吗
Are the lights on in this room?
是的
Yes.
你现在在威斯敏斯特吗
Are you now in the City of Westminster?
不是
No.
你喜欢大喝一杯吗
Do you enjoy toast?
非常喜欢
Very much.
是还是不是
Yes or no.
是的
Yes.
你是否曾在争吵中对伴侣实施过
Have you ever physically assaulted a significant other
身体暴力
during an argument?
你知道答案的
Girl, you know I have.
请回答是或否
Again, yes or no.
是
Yes.
并且很享受
Enthusiastically.
你带隐形眼镜吗
Do you wear contact lenses?
是
Yes.
抽烟吗
Do you smoke cigarettes?
否
No.
你现在坐着吗
Are you seated at the moment?
是
Yes.
现在是上午还是下午
Is it morning or afternoon?
下午能回到刚才的艾森克人格问卷吗
Afternoon. Can we go back to the EPQs?
那些问题更有意思
They’re more fun.
琪亚娜是你母亲吗
Is your mother’s name Quiana?
是
Yes.
你什么时候开始知道死危病毒的存在的
When did you first become aware of Severus?
什么是死危病毒
What’s Severus?
你是不是一个失败的父亲
Have you ever failed to support any child of yours?
额
Uh...
情感上失败吧
only emotionally.
是或否
Yes or no.
是
Yes.
我没给你集成工程师的工作 你是否心怀怨恨
Were you resentful that I passed you over for the CI job?
-你他妈还想怎样 -是或否
-I’m fucking human. -Yes or no.
我没给你集成工程师的工作 你是否心怀怨恨
Were you resentful that I passed you over for the job?
是
Yes.
你是否为了报复偷走了死危病毒
Did you steal Severus as a means of getting even?
否
No.
你第一次知道死危病毒的存在是什么时候
When did you first become aware of Severus?
两个月前
About two months ago.
你怎么知道的
How did you become aware?
出于职业限制
Professional restrictions prevent me
我无法回答这个问题
from answering the question.
你怎么知道的
How did you become aware?
我无法回答
Same answer.
是你的病人泄露的吗
Did a patient divulge the information to you?
我无法回答
Same answer.
除了战争
Outside of war,
你还杀过人吗
have you ever killed another person?
请你定义什么是战争
Define "war."
英国与其他国家或非国家行为体之间的
Declared or undeclared conflict between the United Kingdom
已宣战或未宣战的冲突
and another country or non-state actor.
否
No.
除了战争以外
Outside of war, have you ever been
你是否经历过枪击捅伤或斗殴
in a shooting, knifing or fight
使人重伤的情况
where someone was seriously injured?
是
Yes.
你背叛过你的国家吗
Have you ever betrayed your country?
否
No.
你和佐伊·沃恩医生
What is your relationship
是什么关系
with Dr. Zoe Vaughan?
她是我的病人
Patient and social acquaintance.
你想休息一下吗
Would you like to take a break?
我挺好的
I’m good.
你的中间名是碧翠斯吗
Is your middle name Beatrice?
否
No.
你的中间名是碧翠斯吗
Is your middle name Beatrice?
否
No.
请如实回答问题
Please answer the question truthfully.
你的中间名是碧翠斯吗
Is your middle name Beatrice?
是
Yeah.
你在收缩你的肛门括约肌吗
Are you tightening your anal sphincter muscle right now?
是
Yes.
你读过韦茅斯和库姆斯写的
Have you read Physiological Stress Response
生理应激反应与测谎欺骗吗
and Polygraph Deception by Weymouth and Coombs?
每一页都读了
Cover to cover.
是或否
Yes or no.
是
Yes.
你能放松你的括约肌吗
Will you please release your sphincter muscle?
当然 乔治
Sure thing, George.
是谁让你把电影票根
Who asked you to plant the movie stub
放到我衣柜的垃圾桶里的
in the wastebasket in my closet?
什么
What?
没人
No one.
你跟多少知道死危病毒的人
How many people are you personally connected with
有联系
who were aware of Severus?
这不是个好问题
That question is inappropriately operational.
你跟多少知道…
How many people are you personally...
乔治 你是集成工程师 你知道我无法回答这个问题
George, you’re CI. You know I can’t answer that.
是你偷窃了死危病毒吗
Did you steal Severus?
否
No.
你是为了钱偷窃死危病毒吗
Did you steal Severus for money?
否
No.
你是为了意识形态问题偷窃死危病毒吗
Did you steal Severus for ideology?
什么意识形态
What ideology?
你是为了信仰偷窃死危病毒吗
Did you steal Severus because of your ideology?
这个问题预设我偷窃了死危病毒
The question assumes I stole Severus.
是或否 这里没有上帝
True or false: There is no God.
否
False.
过去三个月里
How many sexual partners
你有多少性伴侣
have you had in the last three months?
两个
Two.
是非题
True or false:
更高的利益
The greater good outweighs
比直接的法律或道德限制更重要
immediate legal or ethical limits.
没有具体的信息我无法回答
Impossible to answer without specifics.
你觉得你比大多数人聪明吗
Do you think you’re smarter than most people?
乔治 我了解我自己
Georgie, I know I am.
是或否
Yes or no.
是
Yes.
你明天晚上愿意
Would you like to come for dinner
来我们家吃晚饭吗
at our home tomorrow evening?
什么
Huh?
我需要你帮忙解决一些问题
I need your help individually to figure something out.
你能来吗
Can you come?
额
Um...
没问题
Yeah, sure.
上次我玩的很开心
Well, I had so much fun last time.
是或否
Yes or no.
这是命令吗
Is this an order?
晚上八点见
We’ll expect you at 8:00.
我们刚刚到底在干吗
Wait, what the fuck did we just learn here?
明天见
See you tomorrow.
你还好吗
You okay?
就是有点紧张
Just nerves.
只差一件事情没搞清楚了
Only one thing left to learn.
它会去那里吗
Will it go there?
那正是我担忧的
That’s what scares me.
它应该会
It should.
我很多年没这么开心了
I haven’t had this much fun in years.
搞这么正式干什么
What’s with the command performance?
请进
Come in.
工作还是社交
Work or social?
是
Yes.
我以为只有我一个
I thought it was just me.
我们都以为
We all did.
所以晚饭在哪里
So where’s this fucking dinner?
-我没做饭 -我们有个游戏要玩
-I didn’t cook. -We have a game.
哦 操 认真的吗
Ah, shit. Really?
我不愿意配合你的游戏
I don’t think I’m willing to submit to this.
这是游戏规则
And here’s how it works.
围着桌子一圈
We go around the table
乔治会问你们每人一个问题
and George will ask each one of you a question.
如果答错了 就输了
And if you get it wrong, you lose.
这不合理
This is inappropriate.
输家
And the loser
别想活着走出去
doesn’t get up from the table.
-我操 -你疯了吗
-For fuck’s sake. -Are you out of your mind?
你们俩疯了 我发誓
The two of you, I swear to God.
-我要走了 -坐下
-I’m leaving. -Sit down.
乔治和凯瑟琳诚挚地邀请你们
You are cordially invited to an evening
度过一个有趣的夜晚
of fun and games with George and Kathryn.
这是一条新地毯
That’s a new rug.
如果你们想在OSRAC委员会面前回答问题的话
Anyone who’d prefer to answer the questions
就走吧
in front of an OSRAC committee is free to go.
为什么这里有一个新地毯
Why is there a new rug?
你们精神错乱了 所有人都是 你们意识到了吗
You’re disturbed. All of you. Do you realize that?
你疯了
You’re sick!
你们才做过爱吧
I mean, you just fuck each other, literally,
来来回回 反反复复
and back and forth and back and forth.
那栋该死的楼里
Is there one normal person
就没有一个正常人吗
inside that entire fucking building?
行
Fine!
我没什么好隐瞒的
I’ve got nothing to hide.
那就从你开始
Then we’ll start with you.
你第一次和弗雷迪上床是什么时候
When did you first sleep with Freddie?
哦 真恶心
Oh, that’s just gross.
下作
Sick.
我道歉
My apologies.
虽然有失风度但很有必要
That was ungentlemanly but necessary.
沃恩博士就是弗雷迪在克拉肯威尔
Dr. Vaughan is the woman Freddie’s been meeting
捷特酒店私会的那个女人
at the Zetter Hotel in Clerkenwell.
狗娘养的
You motherfucker.
七八周前
Seven or eight weeks ago.
-谢谢 -这是在开玩笑么
- Thank you. - Is that a joke?
和他 为什么
With him? Why?
这是操纵手段
Manipulation.
她认为迟早需要从他身上获取情报
She thought she’d need something from him eventually.
得了吧 别这么混蛋 有没有可能只是
Ah, come on. Don’t be a prick. Isn’t it just possible...
不可能
No, it isn’t.
他说得对
He’s right.
在重新定位被发现后
After the redirect was discovered,
你通知了沃恩博士对吗
you alerted Dr. Vaughan, didn’t you?
没错
Yes, that’s right.
你会想知道这个的
You’ll want to know about this.
我要你办件事
I need you to do something.
我任你摆布 什么事
I am putty in your hands. What is it?
你告诉我重新定位的时候
So, you told me about the redirect,
知道我会采取行动为乔治打掩护
knowing that I would take action to cover for George.
他接下来三小时会穿过波兰
He’s traveling across Poland for the next three hours.
别等了
Don’t wait.
是
Yes.
克拉丽莎
Clarissa.
你他妈想干嘛
What the fuck do you want?
来祝贺你
Only to congratulate you.
你是我见过最会操纵测谎仪的人
You’re the best manipulator of the polygraph I’ve ever seen.
-我没撒谎 -我知道
-I didn’t lie. -I know.
你不需要撒谎
You didn’t need to.
你和这些事毫无瓜葛
You had nothing to do with any of it.
在电影院留票让我发现是你的主意
Was it your idea to plant the movie ticket so I’d find it
还是别人的
or someone else’s?
什么电影票
What movie ticket?
确实引起了我的注意
Did catch my eye.
以我的专业性判断这并不难
Not so hard to do, given my profession.
你他妈在说什么鬼话 乔治
The hell are you talking about, George?
是施蒂格利茨先找你提议
Was Stieglitz the one who came to you with the idea
偷走死危病毒的吗
of stealing Severus?
这样最合理
That would make the most sense.
既能扰乱莫斯科 又能陷害威胁施蒂格利茨的凯瑟琳
To destabilize Moscow, to implicate Kathryn,
还能把我从你路上踢开
who threatened Stieglitz, and to move me out of your way.
一举三得
Three birds, one stone.
总之你从大楼里
Somehow, you removed
移除了死危病毒恶意软件
the Severus malware from the building.
但你对自己的计划感到太兴奋
But you got excited about your plan,
喝多了向沃恩博士泄露了这事
you drank too much and told Dr. Vaughan about it.
你没想到的是
What you didn’t know
她的宗教信仰有多虔诚
is how profound her religious beliefs are.
你现在反咬我
You’re turning on me
是想掩盖自己的叛国行为
to cover up your own treasonous actions.
那种信仰不允许她
The kind of beliefs that would not permit her
坐视数万人因核泄漏丧生
to allow the deaths of tens of thousands in a meltdown.
都是妄想
This is a fantasy.
全是他妈的妄想
This is all one of his fucking fantasies.
所以最初我也很困惑
It’s why I had a hard time at first.
这不是一个计划 而是两个
It wasn’t one plan, you see, it was two.
独立却又环环相扣
Separate but interlocking.
既相互配合又彼此对抗
Working for and against each other.
你操纵我 让帕夫留克逃脱
You manipulated me so Pavlichuk could escape.
你和弗雷迪对凯瑟琳如法炮制
And you and Freddie did the same with Kathryn
这样就让她灭口他来保全我
so she would have him killed to bail me out.
因果循环
Causa et effectus.
对吗
Isn’t that right?
你们俩让这事变得太容易了
You two make it almost easy.
你们唯一在乎的只有彼此
The only thing you give a shit about is each other.
郑重声明 我早就知道
For the record, I knew.
但我还是做了 因为必须这么做
I did it anyway because it needed doing.
你还把我引到苏黎世
And you had me lured to Zurich.
我以为是要买回死危病毒
I thought I was buying back Severus,
结果你让我看起来像是在卖出
but you made it look like I was selling.
你在缅甸开的那个账户 是你自己操作的
You opened the account in Myanmar yourself,
对不对
didn’t you?
全是臆测
This is all conjecture.
结果发现
Turns out
缅甸方面很配合
Myanmar does cooperate.
只要找对人就行
You just have to know who to ask.
拉兹曼还欠我人情
Razman still owes me.
死危病毒是个好计划
Severus was a good plan.
再来十次我还会做同样选择
I’d do it again, ten times out of ten.
这个构思很巧妙
It was a decent frame,
本来可以终结这场该死的战争
and it would have ended the fucking war!
这是正确 勇敢 高尚的
It was right, it was brave, and it was noble.
哪个是你杀米查姆的理由
Which one was the reason you killed Meacham?
因为正确 还是因为高尚
Because it was right or because it was noble?
因为必要
Because it was necessary.
我从没告诉过你这个游戏的名字
I never told you all the name of the game.
什么游戏 凯瑟琳
What’s the game, Kathryn?
看谁先拔枪
"See Who Picks Up the Gun."
妈的
For fuck’s sake.
来吧 乔治
Come on, George.
怎样 给我戴上手铐带走
What? You take me out in handcuffs,
你说你的 我说我的 然后呢
you say your bit, I say mine, then what?
你还是会完蛋
You still go down.
她或许没事 但你肯定完蛋
Maybe she doesn’t, but you will.
你没有任何实锤证据
You got nothing... nothing hard.
只有怀疑 传闻和枕边风
You got suspicions, hearsay and pillow talk.
还有你的认罪录音
And, you know, your recorded confession.
谈谈你的投降条件
Shall we discuss the terms of your surrender?
你在虚张声势
You’re bluffing.
你该在船上就杀了我 乔治
You should’ve killed me on the boat, George.
我不介意你们做的事
Now, I don’t mind what you two did.
你们救了人
You saved lives.
但别再插手我的婚姻
But don’t ever fuck with my marriage again.
好的
Okay.
弗雷迪 桌子
Freddie. Table.
亲爱的 我们需要地毯
Darling, we need the rug.
九楼
Ninth floor.
电梯门开
Doors opening.
电梯下行
Lift going down.
电梯门关
Doors closing.
斯托克斯的事真糟糕
Terrible about Stokes.
-太蹊跷了 -是啊
-So strange. -Mm.
就这么消失了
Disappearing like that.
这行当确实危险
It’s a very dangerous line of work.
确实如此
Mm, I’ll say.
鉴于你的成就
Given all you’ve accomplished,
或许该考虑退休了 亚瑟
maybe it’s time to consider stepping away, Arthur.
先迈出去
Feet first.
二楼
Second floor.
电梯门开
Doors opening.
随你便
Any way you like.
电梯下行
Lift going down.
他完全慌了
He’s completely rattled.
太棒了
Fantastic.
够他一个月睡不着觉了
He won’t be able to sleep for a whole month.
他没慌
He wasn’t rattled.
他把所有功劳都揽走了
He took credit for the whole thing.
中情局那帮人正围着他大献殷勤
The CIA is lap dancing all over him.
都是假象
It’s a fiction.
他演不了多久
He won’t be able to keep it up forever.
施蒂格利茨让我感到无聊
And Stieglitz bores me.
我们 聊聊你吧
Let’s... let’s talk about you.
为什么不直接问我电影票的事
Why didn’t you just ask me about the movie ticket?
看我会不会撒谎
Hmm? See if I was lying?
信任
Faith.
你从不犯这种低级错误
You’d never be that sloppy.
电影票 太可笑了
A movie stub. Please.
确实
Well, exactly.
简直侮辱智商
It’s almost insulting.
-我知道你不会骗我 -除非必要
-I knew you’d never lie to me. -Only if I had to.
当然
Obviously.
有件事
One thing.
斯托克斯存进瑞士银行账户的
The, uh, seven million pounds
七百万英镑还在吗
Stokes put into the Swiss bank account?
还在
Still there.
哦 是吗
Oh. Is it?